I want to talk about the election.
أود الحديث عن إلإنتخابات.
For the first time in the United States, a predominantly white group of voters
لاول مرة في الولايات المتحدة،الغالب من مجموع الناخبين البيض
voted for an African-American candidate for President.
صوتت لمرشح أفريقي-امريكي للرئاسة.
And in fact Barack Obama did quite well.
وحقيقة باراك اوباما ابلي بلاءً حسناً.
He won 375 electoral votes.
كسب 375 صوتا الكترونياً
And he won about 70 million popular votes
وكسب حوالي 70 مليون من اصوات الشعب
more than any other presidential candidate --
أكثر من اي مرشح رئاسة آخر،
of any race, of any party -- in history.
من اي عرق، اي حزب، في التاريخ
If you compare how Obama did against how John Kerry had done four years earlier --
إذا قارنت ما فعل اوباما مقابل ما فعل جون كيري قبل اربعة سنوات --
Democrats really like seeing this transition here,
الديموقراطيون حقاً يُحبون رؤية هذا إلإنتقال هُنا.
where almost every state becomes bluer, becomes more democratic --
حيث غالباً كل ولاية تصير زرقاء، تصير أكثر ديمقراطية --
even states Obama lost, like out west,
وحتي ولايات خسرها اوباما، كالتي في الغرب.
those states became more blue.
هذه الولايات تصبح اكثر زرقة
In the south, in the northeast, almost everywhere
في الجنوب، في الشمال الشرقي، تقريباً في كل مكان
but with a couple of exceptions here and there.
مع بعض الإستثناءات هناوهناك.
One exception is in Massachusetts.
أحدهم في ماساشوستس.
That was John Kerry's home state.
تلك ولاية جون كيري المركزية.
No big surprise, Obama couldn't do better than Kerry there.
ليست مفاجأة كبيره، اوباما لم يفعل أفضل من كيري هناك.
Or in Arizona, which is John McCain's home,
أو في اريزونا، حيث معقل جون ماكين،
Obama didn't have much improvement.
أوباما لم يكن لديه تحسن كثير.
But there is also this part of the country, kind of in the middle region here.
ولكن هنالك هذا الجُزء من البلاد، كما التي في المنطقة الوسطي هنا.
This kind of Arkansas, Tennessee, Oklahoma, West Virginia region.
كمناطق اركنساس، تنسي، اوكلاهوما، غرب فيرجينيا.
Now if you look at '96, Bill Clinton --
ألآن إذا نظرنا للعام 96، بيل كلينتون،
the last Democrat to actually win -- how he did in '96,
اخر ديمقراطي فاز فعلاً، كيف فعل في 96،
you see real big differences in this part of the country right here,
ترون فرق شاسع في هذا الجزء من البلاد هُنا --
the kind of Appalachians, Ozarks, highlands region, as I call it:
كألأبلاشيان، ألأوزاركس، مناطق المرتفعات، كما أُسميها.
20 or 30 point swings
20 أو 30 نقطة تُرجح
from how Bill Clinton did in '96 to how Obama did
من كيف فعل بيل كلينتون في 96 إلي كيف فعل اوباما
in 2008.
فى 2008
Yes Bill Clinton was from Arkansas, but these are very, very profound differences.
نعم بيل كلينتون كان من اركنساس، ولكن هذه فروقات عميقة جداً جداً.
So, when we think about parts of the country like Arkansas, you know.
إذا، عندما نفكر حول اجزاء من البلاد كأركنساس، أتعلم.
There is a book written called, "What's the Matter with Kansas?"
هنالك كتاب مخطوط يسمي، ما الامر مع كنساس؟
But really the question here -- Obama did relatively well in Kansas.
ولكن حقيقة المسألة هنا -- أوباما ابلي بلاءً حسنأً في كنساس.
He lost badly but every Democrat does.
وخسر بشكل سئ ولكن كل ديقراطي يفعل.
He lost no worse than most people do.
هو خسر ليس أسوأ مما يفعل معظم الناس.
But yeah, what's the matter with Arkansas?
ولكن نعم، ما هو الامر مع اركنساس؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And when we think of Arkansas we tend to have pretty negative connotations.
وعندما نفكر باركنساس نميل إلي إحتواء دلالات سلبية.
We think of a bunch of rednecks, quote, unquote, with guns.
نفكر ببعض المتخلفين، أقتباس، نهاية إقتباس، يحملون البنادق.
And we think people like this probably don't want to vote
ونحن نعتقد ان أُناس كهولاء ربما لايرغبون بالتصويت
for people who look like this and are named Barack Obama.
لإشخاص يبدون كهذا، ويسمون باراك اوباما.
We think it's a matter of race. And is this fair?
نحن نعتقد انها مسألة اعراق. وهل هذا عدل؟
Are we kind of stigmatizing people from Arkansas, and this part of the country?
هل نحن نوعاً ما نوصم الاشخاص من اركنساس، وهذا جزء من البلاد؟
And the answer is: it is at least partially fair.
والجواب هو، ذلك علي ألاقل عادل جزئياً
We know that race was a factor, and the reason why we know that
نعلم أن العرِق كان عاملاً، وسبب علمنا بذلك
is because we asked those people.
لاننا سألنا هولاء الأشخاص.
Actually we didn't ask them, but when they conducted
في الواقع نحن لم نسألهم،ولكن عندما يجرون
exit polls in every state,
إستطلاعات آراء الناخبين في كل ولاية،
in 37 states, out of the 50,
في 37 ولاية من 50 ولاية،
they asked a question, that was pretty direct, about race.
سآلوا سؤالاً، كان بشكل مباشر، عن العِرق.
They asked this question.
سألو هذا السؤال.
In deciding your vote for President today, was the race
للبت بصوتك للرئاسة اليوم، هل كان لعِرق
of the candidate a factor?
المرشح تأثير؟
We're looking for people that said, "Yes, race was a factor;
نبحث عن الاشخاص الذين قالو "نعم، العرق كان عاملاً;
moreover it was an important factor, in my decision,"
بل كان عاملاً مهماً، في قراري".
and people who voted for John McCain
وألاشخاص الذين صوتوا لجون ماكين
as a result of that factor,
ونتيجة لذلك العامل،
maybe in combination with other factors, and maybe alone.
ربما بالدمج مع عوامل اُخرى، وربما وحده.
We're looking for this behavior among white voters
نحن نبحث عن هذا السلوك بين الناخبين البيض،
or, really, non-black voters.
أو حقيقةً، الناخبين غير السود.
So you see big differences in different parts
كما ترون، إختلافات كبيرة في مناطق مختلفه
of the country on this question.
من البلاد، في هذا السؤال.
In Louisiana, about one in five white voters
في لويزيانا، حوالي 1 من 5 من البيض الناخبين
said, "Yes, one of the big reasons why I voted against Barack Obama
قال، "نعم، من الاسباب الرئيسية لتصويتي ضد باراك اوباما
is because he was an African-American."
لأنه من الافارقة-الامريكان".
If those people had voted for Obama,
لو صوت هولاءِ لاوباما،
even half of them, Obama would have won Louisiana safely.
أو حتي نصفهم، لكان لأوباما ان يكسب لويزيانا بامان.
Same is true with, I think, all of these states you see on the top of the list.
ينطبق الشي نفسه، باعتقادي، علي كل هذه الولايات التي ترون بأعلي القائمة.
Meanwhile, California, New York, we can say, "Oh we're enlightened"
في الوقت نفسه، كاليفورنيا، نيويورك. يمكن القول، "اوه لقد إستنرنا،"
but you know, certainly a much lower incidence of this
ولكن أتعلمون، بالتاكيد أحداث اقل بكثير من هذه
admitted, I suppose,
اعترف، وافترض،
manifestation of racially-based voting.
من مظاهر إستناد التصويت علي العِرق
Here is the same data on a map.
هنا نفس البيانات علي خريطة.
You kind of see the relationship between
كما ترون العلاقه بين
the redder states of where more people responded and said,
الولايات الحمراء حيث اكثرالاشخاص الذين اجابو وقالوا،
"Yes, Barack Obama's race was a problem for me."
"نعم، عِرق باراك اوباما كان مشكلة لي"
You see, comparing the map to '96, you see an overlap here.
أترون، بمقارنة الخريطة بالعام 1996، ستري تداخل هنا.
This really seems to explain
وهذا حقيقة يوضح
why Barack Obama did worse
لماذا كان باراك اوباما سيئاً
in this one part of the country.
في هذا الجزء من البلاد.
So we have to ask why.
ولذا يتعين علينا ان نسأل لماذا.
Is racism predictable in some way?
هل العنصرية متوقعة بشكل أو آخر؟
Is there something driving this?
هل هناك شئ يقود هذا؟
Is it just about some weird stuff that goes on in Arkansas
ام فقط حول أشياء غريبة تحدث في أركنساس
that we don't understand, and Kentucky?
ذلك ما لانفهمه، وكنتاكي؟
Or are there more systematic factors at work?
أم أن هناك عوامل اكثر منهجية في العمل؟
And so we can look at a bunch of different variables.
ولذا يمكننا النظر إلي مجموعة من المتغيرات المختلفة.
These are things that economists and political scientists look at all the time --
هذه إلاشياء التي يراها الإقتصاديون وعلماء السياسة في كل وقت --
things like income, and religion, education.
أشياء كمعدل الدخل، والديانة، التعليم.
Which of these seem to drive
واي من هذه يبدو كدافع
this manifestation of racism
هذه المظاهر من العنصرية
in this big national experiment we had on November 4th?
في هذه التجربة الوطنية الكبيرة لدينا في الرابع من نوفمبر؟
And there are a couple of these that have
وهناك بعض من التي لها
strong predictive relationships,
علاقات قوية بالتنبؤ --
one of which is education,
والتي منها التعليم.
where you see the states with the fewest years of schooling
حيث ترون الولايات ألاقل سنوات دراسية
per adult are in red,
للبالغين، في الأحمر،
and you see this part of the country, the kind of Appalachians region,
ونري هذا الجزء من البلاد، منطقة الابلانشيا،
is less educated. It's just a fact.
أقل تعليماً. مجرد حقيقة.
And you see the relationship there
ونري العلاقة هناك
with the racially-based voting patterns.
مع أنماط التصويت المبني علي العِرق.
The other variable that's important is
المفارقة المهمة الآخرى هي
the type of neighborhood that you live in.
نوعية ألاحياء التي تعيش فيها.
States that are more rural --
الولايات الأكثر ريفية،
even to some extent of the states like New Hampshire and Maine --
وحتي بعض الولايات مثل نيوهامشير و ماين،
they exhibit a little bit of
عرضت بعض من
this racially-based voting against Barack Obama.
هذا التصويت المؤسس علي العرِق ضد بآراك أوباما.
So it's the combination of these two things: it's education
إذاً هو الجمع بين هذين الامرين. التعليم
and the type of neighbors that you have,
ونوعية الاحياء التي لدينا،
which we'll talk about more in a moment.
والتي سوف نتحدث أكثر عنها بعد قليل.
And the thing about states like Arkansas and Tennessee
بخصوص الولايات كأركنساس وتنيسي
is that they're both very rural,
فأن كلاهما مناطق ريفية جداً،
and they are educationally impoverished.
وهم قليلو التعليم
So yes, racism is predictable.
إذاً نعم، العنصرية متوقعة.
These things, among maybe other variables,
هذه الاشياء، ربما بين مفارقات أُخري،
but these things seem to predict it.
ولكن هذه الأمور تبدو انها تتنبي به.
We're going to drill down a little bit more now,
سنتعمق للداخل اكثر الان،
into something called the General Social Survey.
في موضوع يسمي المسح الإجتماعي العام.
This is conducted by the University of Chicago
وهذه تُجري بواسطة جامعة شيكاغو
every other year.
كل عامين
And they ask a series of really interesting questions.
ويسألون سلسلة من الاسئلة المشّوقة حقاً.
In 2000 they had particularly interesting questions
في العام 2000 كان لديهم أسئلة مشّوقة خاصة
about racial attitudes.
عن المواقف العِرقية.
One simple question they asked is,
سألوا سؤال واحد بسيط هو،
"Does anyone of the opposite race live in your neighborhood?"
"هل يعيش في منطقتكم اعراق مختلفة؟"
We can see in different types of communities that the results are quite different.
يمكن ان نري نوعيات مختلفة من المجتمعات بنتائج مختلفة تماماً.
In cites, about 80 percent of people
في المُدن، حوالي 80 من نسبة الاشخاص
have someone whom they consider a neighbor of another race,
لديهم شخص يعتبرونه جار، من عرق مختلف.
but in rural communities, only about 30 percent.
ولكن في المجتمعات الريفيه، النسبة فقط حوالي 30.
Probably because if you live on a farm, you might not have a lot of neighbors, period.
لانه من المحتمل اذا عشت في مزرعة، لربما لم يكن لديك عدد من الجيران، ابداً
But nevertheless, you're not having a lot of interaction with people
ومع ذلك، أنت ليس لك تداخل مع أشخاص
who are unlike you.
ليسوا مثلك.
So what we're going to do now is take the white people in the survey
إِذاً ما سنفعله ان نأخذ الاشخاص البِيض في إستطلاع
and split them between those who have black neighbors --
ونقسمهم بين هولاء الذين لديهم جيران سُود
or, really, some neighbor of another race --
أو حقيقةً، جيران من أعراق أُخري.
and people who have only white neighbors.
والأشخاص الذين لديهم فقط جيران بيض.
And we see in some variables
ونحن نري في بعض التغييّرات
in terms of political attitudes, not a lot of difference.
من حيث المواقف السياسية ، وليس هناك الكثير من الفرق
This was eight years ago, some people were more Republican back then.
كان هذا قبل ثمانية أعوام مضت، بعض الأشخاص كان أكثرهم جمهوريين حينها.
But you see Democrats versus Republican,
ولكن تري ديمقراطيين و جمهوريين،
not a big difference based on who your neighbors are.
ليس هناك خلاف كبير حول هوية الجيران.
And even some questions about race -- for example
وحتي إسئلة حول العرِق، مثال
affirmative action, which is kind of a political question,
العمل إلإيجابي، والذي يعتبر سؤال سياسي،
a policy question about race, if you will --
سؤال سياسي حول العرق، إذا صح التعبير.
not much difference here.
لا فرق كبير هُنا.
Affirmative action is not very popular frankly, with white voters, period.
العمل إلإيجابي لا يحظي بشهرة جيدة صراحة في اوساط الناخبين البيض، أبداُ.
But people with black neighbors and people with mono-racial neighborhoods
ولكن الاشخاص الذين يجاورون السود والأشخاص في المناطق الآحادية الاعراق
feel no differently about it really.
لا يشعرون بفرق حقيقي حوله.
But if you probe a bit deeper and get a bit more personal if you will,
ولكن إذا بحثنا عميقاً، شخصي قليلاً، فلنقل،
"Do you favor a law banning interracial marriage?"
"هل تؤيد قرار يمنع زواج الاعراق المختلفة؟"
There is a big difference.
هناك فرق كبير.
People who don't have neighbors of a different race
الاشخاص الذين لاجيران ملونين لهم
are about twice as likely
احتمال ضِعفهم اقرب
to oppose interracial marriage as people who do.
أن يعترض علي زواج الأعراق المختلفة، من المؤيدين له.
Just based on who lives in your immediate neighborhood around you.
فقط إستناداً علي الذين يعيشون بجوارهم في الحي.
And likewise they asked, not in 2000, but in the same survey in 1996,
وبطريقة مماثلة سألوا، ليس في العام 2000، ولكن في ذات المسح في العام 1996،
"Would you not vote for a qualified black president?"
"أيمكن أن تنتخب رئيس أسود مؤهل ؟"
You see people without neighbors who are African-American who
نلاحظ الأشخاص الذين ليس لديهم جيران من الأفارقة-الأمريكان
were much more likely to say, "That would give me a problem."
الراجح ان يكون قولهم، "هذا سيسبب لي مشكلة."
So it's really not even about urban versus rural.
إذاً حقاً ليست القضية بين الحضر مقابل الارياف.
It's about who you live with.
ولكن عن الذين يعيشون معك.
Racism is predictable. And it's predicted by
العنصرية متوقعة.وهي متوقعة
interaction or lack thereof with people unlike you, people of other races.
بالتفاعل أو إنعدامه مع أشخاص ليسوا مثلك، أشخاص من أعراق آُخري.
So if you want to address it,
وإذا أردت التصدي له
the goal is to facilitate interaction with people of other races.
الهدف هو تسهيل التفاعل مع اشخاص من أعراق آُخري.
I have a couple of very obvious, I suppose,
عندي نقاط واضحة جداً، أفترض،
ideas for maybe how to do that.
أفكار ربما في كيفية عمل ذلك.
I'm a big fan of cities.
أنا هاوٍ كبير للمدن.
Especially if we have cites that are diverse and sustainable,
لأسيما ونحن نملك شواهد علي انها متنوعة و مستقرة،
and can support people of different ethnicities and different income groups.
ويمكن ان تدعم اشخاص من أعراق مختلفه و فئات دخل متفاوتة.
I think cities facilitate more of the kind of networking,
أعتقد المدن تسهل ترابط اكثر،
the kind of casual interaction than you might have on a daily basis.
وتفاعل عفوي قد يكون لديكم بشكل يومي.
But also not everyone wants to live in a city, certainly not a city like New York.
ولكن بلا شك ليس كل شخص يود العيش في المدينة، بالتأكيد ليس في مدينة كنيويورك.
So we can think more about things like street grids.
إذاً بمكن ان نفكر اكثر بأشياء كشبكات الشوارع.
This is the neighborhood where I grew up in East Lansing, Michigan.
هذا هو الحي الذي نشأت فيه في شرق لانسينق، ميتشيغان.
It's a traditional Midwestern community, which means you have real grid.
أنه مجتمع غرب وسطي تقليدي، مما يعني شبكة حقيقية.
You have real neighborhoods and real trees, and real streets you can walk on.
حيث توجد أحياء حقيقية وأشجار حقيقية، وطرقات حقيقية يمكن السير عليها.
And you interact a lot with your neighbors --
وتتفاعل كثيراً مع الجيران،
people you like, people you might not know.
أشخاص تُعجب بهم، أشخاص ربما لاتعرفهم.
And as a result it's a very tolerant community,
والنتيجة هي مجتمع متسامح جداً،
which is different, I think, than something like this,
والذي يختلف، أعتقد، عن شئ كهذا،
which is in Schaumburg, Illinois,
وهو في شاومبيرق، إلينويس.
where every little set of houses has their own cul-de-sac
حيث كل مجموعة صغيرة من البيوت لديها شوارعها الخاصة
and drive-through Starbucks and stuff like that.
ومدخل خِلال ستارباكس وأشياء كهذه.
I think that actually this type of urban design,
وأعتقد فعلاً أن هذا النوع من تصاميم المدن،
which became more prevalent in the 1970s and 1980s --
والذي أصبح شائعاً في السبعينيات والثمانيات،
I think there is a relationship between that and the country becoming
أعتقد أن هناك علاقة بين هذا وبين أن تصبح البلد
more conservative under Ronald Reagan.
أكثر تحفظاً، تحت حكم رونالد ريغان.
But also here is another idea we have --
ولكن أيضاً، هنالك فكره آخري لدينا --
is an intercollegiate exchange program
هو برنامج تبادل الطلاب
where you have students going from New York abroad.
حيث هناك طلبة بذهبون من نيويورك إلي خارج الحدود،
But frankly there are enough differences within the country now
ولكن بصراحة هناك فوارق كافية في البلاد الآن
where maybe you can take a bunch of kids from NYU,
حيث ربما يمكنك أخذ مجموعة من الطلبة من جامعة نيويورك،
have them go study for a semester at the University of Arkansas,
ونلحقهم بالدراسة لفصل دراسي في جامعه أركنساس،
and vice versa. Do it at the high school level.
والعكس بالعكس. نقوم بذلك علي مستوي المدارس الثانوية.
Literally there are people who might be in school in Arkansas or Tennessee
حرفياً هنالك أشخاص في مدارس في اركنساس أو تينيسي،
and might never interact in a positive affirmative way
وربما لم يتفاعلوا بطريقة إيجابية
with someone from another part of the country, or of another racial group.
مع شخص من منطقة آخري من البلاد، أو جماعة عرقية آُخرى.
I think part of the education variable we talked about before
أعتقد جزء من إختلاف التعليم الذي تحدثنا عنه سابقاً
is the networking experience you get when you go to college
وهو خبرة الترابط التي تُكستب عند إلالتحاق بالكلية
where you do get a mix of people that you might not interact with otherwise.
حيث تختلط باشخاص لربما لن تتفاعل معهم من ناحية أخري.
But the point is, this is all good news,
ولكن النقطة هى، هذه كلها أخبار جيدة.
because when something is predictable,
لأن عندما يكون هناك شئ متوقع،
it is what I call designable.
إنه ما أسميه قابل للتصميم.
You can start thinking about solutions to solving that problem,
يمكنك البدء بالتفكير بحلول لحل تلك المشكلة.
even if the problem is pernicious and as intractable as racism.
حتي وإن كانت المشكلة خبيثة و مستعصية كما العُنصُرية.
If we understand the root causes of the behavior
إذا فهمنا الاسباب الجذرية للسلوك
and where it manifests itself and where it doesn't,
واين تتجلي واين لا.
we can start to design solutions to it.
يمكننا البدء بتصميم حلول له.
So that's all I have to say. Thank you very much.
هذا كل ما أود قوله. شكراً جزيلاً لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)